

Esteban Basili

Full Stack Web Developer | Architect | BIM Specialist

Details

+49 1520 9431181
me@estebanbasili.com
Linkedin
GitHub

Skills

Instagram

Creative Thinking
Leadership
Resourcefulness
Organisational
Solutions oriented
Iterative working
Motivating others
Strategic Thinking
Openness to criticism
Drive and Initiative

Languages

Spanish (Castilian) Native

Enalish

Proficient
First Certificate (C1)
Cambridge University

German

Intermediate
Zertifikat Deutsch (B2.2)
Goethe Institut

Profile

Full Stack Web Developer with a sensibility for human-centred design, user experience and multidisciplinarity as key values to create meaningful and impactful products.

Architect and BIM Specialist with more than 10 years of experience in design and construction, and engaged in the digitalisation of the industry.

Professional history

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Ironhack

May 2022 - Jul 2022 ▷ Remote.

Sabbatical

Oct 2021 - Mar 2022 ▷ Mexico, Costa Rica, Argentina, Brazil.

• Inner work and personal development.

Project Architect and BIM Specialist/Manager, Hyphen A GmbH

Oct 2018 - Sep 2021 Derlin, Germany

- Managed the BIM data production and exchange in projects of the logistic sector for Amazon (from 60.000m² to 100.000m²).
- Lead the BIM Coordination including managing sub-contractors BIM teams, gaining expertise in understanding BEP and EIR requirements and managing CDE platforms.
- Developed BIM Standards, family libraries and dynamo scripts.
- Co-ordinated in-house training in BIM authoring tools.

Consulting Architect (Prototypes for industrial wood houses), Tapebicuá

Feb 2018 - Sept 2018 ▷ Gobernador Virasoro, Argentina

• Consulted the management team in the design and construction phase, reducing the overall lead times by 20%.

Partner, Architect and BIM Manager, IR arquitectura

Jun 2015 - Ago 2018 ▷ Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Managed and delivered projects from schematic design through design development to construction administration.
- Developed standards for efficiency in project management collaborative workflows and phase transitions.
- Promoted the digitalization and BIM Implementation.
 (See Portfolio for featured projects)

Technical skills

Stack

HTML and CSS

Javascript

MongoDB

Express.js

React.js

Node.js

Git and GitHub

Python

AEC Specific Technologies

Revit

Dynamo

BIM 360

Aconex

Navisworks

Autocad

Revizto

Solibri

Bluebeam Revu

3ds Max

Graphic Design

Indesign

Illustrator

Photoshop

Hobbies

Travelling

Meditation and Yoga

Photography

Cycling

Education

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Ironhack

May 2022 - Jul 2022 ▷ Remote.

- Project 1. The Museum Visitor (Link to site GitHub)
- Project 2. PlantApp (Link to site GitHub)
- Project 3. PSC Pet Social Club (Link to site GitHub Back | Front)

Universidad de Buenos Aires. Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Urbanismo, Architect Diploma (6 years Degree)

Mar 2007 - May 2015 ▷ Buenos Aires, Argentina.

Academic experience and Internships

Revit Teacher Assistant. BIM Course.

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018 ▷ Universidad de Buenos Aires

Teacher assistant in the class led by Arch. Javier Nuñez.

Revit Teacher. Revit a Medida.

Feb 2017 - Jan 2019 ▷ Buenos Aires, Argentina

Led one-on-one and group lessons of Revit and BIM.

Arch. Designer/Intern, 4L Arquitectura/KLM Arquitectos/A3 Arquitectos.

Mar 2010 - May 2015 ▷ Buenos Aires.

• Collaborated on schematic design, design competitions and architectural visualisation.

Workshops and courses

Public Speaking and Strategic Communication.

2018 ▷ Universidad de San Isidro, Buenos Aires, Argentina Course in effective communication in contexts of public exposure.

Wood Architecture.

2016 ▶ Universidad de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina Postgraduate course focused on the techniques of wood use in construction.

Technical Project. Workshop.

2013 ▷ Universidad Nacional Del Comahue, Neuquén, Argentina.

Workshop led by Architect PhD. Juan Herreros (Herreros Arguitectos).